# **Darla Gallo**

#### **Clinical Pharmacist - Enclara Health**

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Darla-Gallo/d4018f76bac6e4d2

Licensed pharmacist with a wealth of experience in many aspects of pharmacy practice. Organized and able to manage multiple tasks while meeting deadlines. Skilled at problem solving using sound clinical judgment.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Clinical Pharmacist

Enclara Health - September 2010 to Present

Consult with nurses, physicians and other health care professionals to ensure appropriate drug therapy for hospice patients.

- Participate in development of symptom/condition management protocols.
- Perform drug utilization review.
- Ensure adherence to DEA regulations and controlled substance laws.
- Review and interpret physician orders.
- Oversee dispensing of medications in accordance with professional standards and practices.
- Oversee technician and clerk processing of CII prescriptions.
- Work with management to improve efficiency of CII fax and hard copy processing.
- Ensure compliance with federal and multi-state controlled substance regulations.
- · Resolve issues involving CII prescriptions.

## Pharmacist Manager, Compounding Division

Boothwyn Pharmacy, Inc - December 2005 to September 2010

Oversaw daily sterile and non-sterile compounding operations following USP 795 and USP 797 guidelines.

- Worked with physicians, veterinarians, sales force, and clients to develop formulations to meet their needs.
- Processed prescriptions for compounded medication using the QS-1 pharmacy system and PCCA "Compounder" software.
- Managed inventory of chemicals, supplies, and batched products.
- Supervised technicians and pharmacy students.
- Worked with President and Controller to reduce costs and maximize profit.

Key Accomplishments:

- Improved workflow, reducing standard order turnaround time from 72 hours to less than 24 hours.
- Redesigned clean room and sterile products program following USP 797 guidelines for clean room design, environmental monitoring, product testing, etc.
- Developed a program for process validation and skip-lot testing of sterile products.
- Reduced chemical inventory by \$20,000 with increased prescription volume.
- Updated record keeping systems (electronic and paper systems).
- Developed 17 alpha hydroxyprogesterone program, leading to contracts with various PBMs.
- Coordinated documentation development and submission for successful DME POS accreditation

## **Supervisor of Pharmacy Appeals and Compliance**

Independence Blue Cross - December 1999 to December 2005

Led a team of clinical pharmacists, pharmacy analysts, and appeals specialists.

- Oversaw processing of first level pharmacy appeals.
- Reengineered the prior authorization process to improve efficiency and accuracy.

- Ensured Pharmacy Services Department adherence to all applicable regulations including development and maintenance of policies and procedures.
- Served as Pharmacy Services Department lead for NCQA accreditation
- Served as a Pharmacy Services Department contact for providers with pharmacy related issues.
- Developed pharmacy related provider communication.
- Participated in Pharmacy and Therapeutics Committee / formulary management activities.

#### **Clinical Pharmacist**

Hospice Pharmacia - June 1998 to December 1999

Performed telephone consultations with nurses and physicians.

- Attended Hospice team meetings.
- Ensured adherence to DEA regulations and controlled substance laws.
- · Performed order entry and documentation.

## **Community Pharmacist**

Abington Pharmacy - November 1993 to June 1998

Counseled patients.

- Compounded and dispensed medications.
- Maintained and upgraded the HBS computer system.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### BS

University of Arizona, College of Pharmacy

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

## Special Training

- Certificate Program in Veterinary Compounding, American College of Apothecaries 2006
- Aseptic Compounding Training, Professional Compounding Centers of America (PCCA) 2006
- Veterinary Pharmaceutical Care and Compounds, (PCCA) 2007
- Advanced Pharmaceutical Care and Compounds for Canines, (PCCA) 2010

### **Professional Activities**

National Association of Boards of Pharmacy

May 1996 to present

Member NAPLEX Review Committee

Member American Pharmacists Association

## Pharmacist Licenses

- Georgia
- Pennsylvania
- New Jersey
- Kentucky
- Virginia